Office 1195, 3675 Market St., Philadelphia, PA 19104 kl696@drexel.edu http://kaili.us

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Kai Li is interested in scholarly communication, open science, and scientometrics, especially (1) how digital research objects, such as software and datasets, and research activities are represented in scientific publications through scientific writing practices and (2) how the existing scientific infrastructure can be improved to facilitate a better integration of scientific research and writing practices. Methodologically, he is interested in applying advanced natural language processing (NLP) and text mining methods on various corpora.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Information Studies

2015 - Present

College of Computing & Informatics

Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

- Proposal defended. Expect to graduate in 2020.
- Dissertation: A quantitative examination of research methods and software in scientific publications
- Committee: Dr. Erjia Yan (Chair), Dr. Jane Greenberg, Dr. Ali Kenner, Dr. Cassidy Sugimoto, Dr. Chaomei Chen, and Dr. Jake Williams

Master of Science in Library and Information Science

2012 - 2013

School of Information Studies

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY

Bachelor's Degree in History

2003 - 2007

School of History

Beijing Normal University, Beijing, China

HONORS & AWARDS

LIS Education and Data Science for the National Digital Platform (LEADS-4-NDP) Fellowship \$2019\$

Drexel University

- Project: Automatic Identification of Publisher Entities to Support Discovery and Navigation (with OCLC)
- Awarded \$5,000 plus travel support

RDA/US Data Share Fellowship

2016 - 2017

Research Data Alliance

- Project: Metadata Standards and Software Citation Practices
- Awarded \$10,000 plus travel support

Student Travel Award

2019

The International Society for Informetrics and Scientometrics

Travel Awards 2016, 2017

Department of Information Science, Drexel University

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

College of Computing & Informatics, Drexel University

• Research Assistant (with Dr. Erjia Yan)

2017 - 2019

- Project: "Building an Entity-based Research Framework to Enhance Digital Services on Knowledge Discovery and Delivery" (funded by the Institute of Museum and Library Services)
- Research Assistant (with Dr. Jane Greenberg)

2016 - 2017

 Project: "Transforming Data Adaptation Science and Service: An Innovative Visual Ontology Application" (funded by Center for Visual & Decision Informatics)

College of Information Studies, Syracuse University

- Research Assistant (with Dr. Kevin Crowston & Dr. Carsten Oesterlund) 2013
 - Project: "Collaborative Research: Focusing Attention to Improve the Performance of Citizen Science Systems - Beautiful Images and Perspective Observers" (funded by the National Science Foundation)
- Research Assistant (with Dr. Jian Qin)

2012 - 2013

PUBLICATIONS Peer-Reviewed Journal Articles

- [J10] Yan, E., Chen, Z., & <u>Li, K.</u> (In press). Authors' status and the perceived quality of their work: measuring citation sentiment change in Nobel papers. *Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology*.
- [J9] <u>Li, K.</u>, Greenberg, J., & Dunic, J. (In press). Data objects and documenting scientific processes: An analysis of data events in biodiversity data papers. *Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology*.
- [J8] <u>Li, K.</u>, Chen, P.-Y., & Yan, E. (2019). Challenges of measuring software impact through citations: An examination of the lme4 R package. *Journal of Informetrics*, 13(1), 449–461. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joi.2019.02.007
- [J7] <u>Li, K.</u>, & Yan, E. (2019). Are NIH-funded publications fulfilling the proposed research? An examination of concept-matchedness between NIH research grants and their supported publications. *Journal of Informetrics*, 13(1), 226–237. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joi.2019.01.001
- [J6] Li, Y., Wu, C., Yan, E., & <u>Li, K.</u> (2018). Will open access increase journal CiteScores? An empirical investigation over multiple disciplines. *PLOS ONE*, 13(8), e0201885. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201885
- [J5] Yan, E., & Li, K. (2018). Which domains do open-access journals do best in? A 5-year longitudinal study. *Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology*, 69(6), 844–856. https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.24002
- [J4] <u>Li, K.</u>, Rollins, J., & Yan, E. (2018). Web of Science use in published research and review papers 1997–2017: a selective, dynamic, cross-domain, content-based analysis. *Scientometrics*, 115(1), 1–20. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11192-017-2622-5

- [J3] Zhao, M., Yan, E., & <u>Li, K.</u> (2018). Data set mentions and citations: A content analysis of full- text publications. *Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology*, 69(1), 32–46. https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23919
- [J2] <u>Li, K.</u> & Yan, E. (2018). Co-mention network of R packages: Scientific impact and clustering structure. *Journal of Informetrics*, 12(1), 87-100. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joi.2017.12.001
- [J1] Li, K., Yan, E., & Feng, Y. (2017). How is R cited in research outputs? Structure, impacts, and citation standard. *Journal of Informetrics*, 11(4), 989–1002. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joi.2017.08.003

Refereed Full Papers in Conference Proceedings

- [C4] <u>Li, K.</u>, & Yan, E. (2019). Using a keyword extraction pipeline to understand concepts in future work sections of research papers. In 17th International Conference on Scientometrics and Informetrics.
- [C3] Feng, Y., Li, K., & Agosto, D.E. (2017). Healthy users' personal health information management from activity trackers: The perspective of gym-goers. In *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of Association for Information Science and Technology* (54: pp. 71-81). https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.2017.14505401009
- [C2] Li, K., Greenberg, J., & Lin, X. (2016). Software Citation, Reuse and Metadata Considerations: An Exploratory Study Examining LAMMPS. In *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Information Science and Technology* (53: pp. 1-10). https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.2016.14505301072
- [C1] Qin, J., & <u>Li, K.</u> (2013). How portable are the metadata standards for scientific data? a proposal for a metadata infrastructure. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Dublin Core and Metadata Applications* (pp. 25–34). https://dcpapers.dublincore.org/pubs/article/view/3670

Refereed Short Papers in Conference Proceedings

- [S2] Pascua, S., <u>Li, K.</u>, & Greenberg, J. (2019). Toward A Metadata Activity Matrix: Conceptualizing and Grounding the Research Life-cycle and Metadata Connections. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Dublin Core and Metadata Applications*.
- [S1] Guerra, J., Wei, Q., <u>Li, K.</u>, Ahumada, L., Winston, F., & Desai, B. R. (2018). Scosy: A Biomedical Collaboration Recommendation System. Presented at the 40th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC), Honolulu, HI, USA.

Refereed Conference Posters

- [P6] Li, K., Chen, P.-Y., & Fang, Z. (2019). Disciplinarity of Software Papers: A Preliminary Analysis. In *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of Association for Information Science and Technology*.
- [P5] Li, K., & Chen, P.-Y. (2019). A preliminary scientometric analysis of the Cross-Strait scientific collaboration. In 17th International Conference on Scientometrics and Informetrics.

[P4] He, J. & Li, K. (2019). How comprehensive is the PubMed Central Open Access full-text database?. Presented at iConference 2019 Annual Meeting, Washington, DC, USA. http://hdl.handle.net/2142/103317

[P3] Li, K. & Chen, PY. (2018). The narrative structure as a citation context in data papers: A preliminary analysis of Scientific Data. In *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of Association for Information Science and Technology*. https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.2018.14505501147

[P2] Li, K. & Xu, S. (2017). Measuring the impact of R packages. In *Proceedings* of the Annual Meeting of Association for Information Science and Technology (54: pp. 739-741). https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.2017.14505401138

[P1] <u>Li, K.</u> (2016). How much can data citation standards be used for scientific software? A crosswalk analysis of data citation standards for software citation needs. Presented in Research Data Alliance 8th Plenary Meeting, Denver, Colorado, September 14-17, 2016.

Book Reviews

[B1] Li, K. (2019). A review of The Politics of Mass Digitization. Education for Information, 35, 361-363. https://doi.org/10.3233/EFI-199011

Doctoral Colloquia (Lightly Peer-Reviewed)

[D2] <u>Li, K.</u> (2019). Quantitative examination of research methods and software in scientific publications. Selected to attend the Doctoral Colloquium at ASIS&T 2019, Melbourne, Australia, October 19, 2019.

[D1] <u>Li, K.</u> (2019). What is the displinarity of software. Selected to attend the Doctoral Forum at 17th International Conference on Scientometrics and Informetrics, Rome, Italy, September 2, 2019.

Non-Refereed Conference Presentations

[T1] Li, K. (2012). RDA in China. Presented at ALA Annual Conference 2012. June $\overline{24}$, $\overline{2012}$. Anaheim, California.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Instructor

College of Computing & Informatics, Drexel University

• INFO 250 (On-site): Information Visualization (Summer '18)

Teaching Assistant

College of Computing & Informatics, Drexel University

- INFO 659: Introduction to Data Analytics (Fall '19)
- INFO 250: Information Visualization (Spring '18)
- INFO 683: Resources for Children (Summer '17)
- CI 101: Introduction to Computing and Informatics (Fall '15)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	Research Intern The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, PA	2016 - 2	2017
	Cataloger Ingram Content Group, Fort Wayne, Indiana	2014 - 2	2015
	Cataloging Librarian Capital Library of China, Beijing, China	2007 - 2	2012

SERVICE & MEMBERSHIPS

Reviewer

- Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology
- Journal of Informetrics
- ullet Scientometrics
- Library Hi Tech
- IEEE Access
- iConference Annual Meeting ('19)
- The American Medical Informatics Association (AMIA) Annual Symposium ('18 '19)

Membership

• The Association for Information Science and Technology (ASIS&T)